<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xt:extensions xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xt="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension/extensions.xsd">
    <xt:extension id="mib">
        <xt:location href="mib-oxygen.zip"/>
        <xt:version>0.4.3</xt:version>
        <xt:oxy_version>15.2+</xt:oxy_version>
        <xt:type>framework</xt:type>
        <xt:author>Mike Olson</xt:author>
        <xt:name>MIB</xt:name>
        <xt:description xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
            <style type="text/css"> .title { font-family:Verdana; font-size:large;
                font-weight:bold;} .body { font-family:Geneva; } .header { font-weight:bold; } code
                { font-size:large; } p { margin:0px; padding:5px; } </style>
            <p class="title">Medieval Irish Bilingualism Oxygen Framework</p>
            <div class="body">
                <p class="header">What's new?</p>
                <p class="header">Version 0.4.3</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p>
                            After a higher-than-average "duh!" factor, I finally figured out that we can have <b>both</b> manual line breaks (i.e. TEI <code>lb</code> elements)
                            <b>as well as text wrapping at the same time</b>. Now, by default, new lines are created for manual line breaks as well as when the text
                            stretches past the edge of the Oxygen window.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            This means, of course, if the Oxygen window is too narrow, a text with line breaks will still wrap.
                            So, I added a new command to allow toggling text wrapping <b>ON</b> and <b>OFF</b> completely.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            You can find this command on the <i>Formats</i> menu with the label <i>Toggle Text Wrap</i>.
                            I also added a button to the Formats toolbar: it's a capital <i>A</i> with
                            a blue arrow pointing backwards (to represent wrapping the text to a new line).
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            By default, text wrapping is <b>ON</b>. Click the button once to turn it <b>OFF</b>.
                            At that point, only manual line breaks within the text will be used to wrap to a new line.
                            Click it again to turn it back <b>ON</b>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Additionally, since text wrapping is <b>ON</b> by default now, it is more difficult to see clearly where manual line breaks are, so
                            I added an icon (an arrow pointing down and back) that is displayed inline within the text to represent manual line breaks.
                            Please let me know what you think of this!
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Finally, I removed the old way of wrapping text (namely with another CSS stylesheet which used to be accessed via the
                            <i>Styles</i> toolbar)
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        I also added many new styles for elements in the TEI Header (mainly in the <code>titleStmt</code> and <code>encodingDesc</code> elements).
                        It's now much closer to handling all possible fields in these elements.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Type dropdowns are also now available for <code>head</code> and <code>title</code> elements in order to distinguish between
                        main and sub headings and titles
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        TIFF Images now supported: When setting a new base directory for the <code>facsimile</code> element,
                        TIFF image files are recognized and added to the list of graphics
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.4.2</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Added links to the end of glosses, so you can get back to the spot in the text that they refer to!
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.4.1</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Updated the CSS so all annotations are shown inline now instead of block (i.e. a new line for each one).
                        This should avoid the problem of inserting whitespace between two annotations where there shouldn't be any
                        (like in the olden days when folks wrote several words together as one word)
                    </li>
                    <li> Added type dropdown to word annotations. You must add the new section to
                        your Contextual Info annotation.xml file (see that template for an example
                        and/or to copy/paste it) </li>
                    <li> Added new CSS to render texts with no line breaks using normal text flow.
                        This is handy for digitized published works in which the physical line
                        breaks are unimportant. To switch between the two modes, select the Styles
                        button/dropdown and then pick the <i>Document Wrap Text</i> option. Brought
                        to you buy the burgeoning HisTEI user community :-) </li>
                    <li>Oh and a couple o' bugs were squashed along the way</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.4.0</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>First release of the framework Medieval Irish Bilingualism</li>
                    <li>First release for HisTEI on GitHub including a new HisTEI default
                        framework</li>
                    <li>Unicode character buttons were added to a menu with shortcut keys</li>
                    <li><code>s</code>, <code>cl</code>, <code>phr</code> and <code>w</code>
                        elements were added</li>
                    <li> Glosses can be inserted and linked using the <code>gloss</code> element and
                            <code>@target</code> attribute. These refer to places in the text marked
                        up with an xml:id using the <code>ab</code>, <code>seg</code> or
                            <code>term</code> elements. </li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </xt:description>
        <xt:license><![CDATA[END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT

The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Mike Olson

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.]]></xt:license>
    </xt:extension>

</xt:extensions>
