<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xt:extensions xmlns:xt="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension"
               xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
               xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/extension/extensions.xsd">
    <xt:extension id="amsterdam">
        <xt:location href="amsterdam-oxygen.zip"/>
        <xt:version>0.3.09</xt:version>
        <xt:oxy_version>15.2+</xt:oxy_version>
        <xt:type>framework</xt:type>
        <xt:author>Mike Olson</xt:author>
        <xt:name>Amsterdam</xt:name>
        <xt:description xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
            <style type="text/css">
                .title { font-family:Verdana; font-size:large; font-weight:bold;}
                .body { font-family:Geneva; }
                .header { font-weight:bold; }
                code { font-size:large; }
                p { margin:0px; padding:5px; }
            </style>
            <p class="title">Emerging Standards Oxygen Framework</p>
            <div class="body">
                <p class="header">What's new?</p>
                <p class="header">Version 0.3.09</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Completely reconfigured keyboard shortcuts - mouse over the buttons to see what the current
                        shortcut is for any button
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.3.08</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        We now have buttons for adding
                        <code>dateline</code>
                        and
                        <code>signed</code>
                        elements into the
                        <code>opener</code>
                        or
                        <code>closer</code>
                        sections.
                        Oh and the closer now includes a
                        <code>dateline</code>
                        element by default now, when a new one is inserted
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Added starting set of suggested values for the
                        <code>type</code>
                        attribute on elements beneath the
                        <code>creation</code>
                        element in the header.
                        But don't worry, you can still type anything there that suits your fancy! And we will surely be
                        adding more as we transcribe more text types (oh and don't call me Shirley!)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Added
                        <code>@script</code>
                        dropdown to<code>handNote</code>s and<code>handShift</code>s,
                        so you can indicate that a hand copied the original, while also indicating what the original
                        hand was - confused yet? ME TOO! ;-)
                    </li>
                    <li>forme work elements (<code>fw</code>) can now be added to paragraphs (<code>p</code>)
                    </li>
                    <li>Made IDs for Orgs editable with textfield, so you can name archives and other organizations</li>
                    <li>Set type dropdown boxes to a default size so it's easier to enter new text into them</li>
                    <li>Force page refresh after updating
                        <code>Facsimile</code>
                        elements, so the dropdown lists are always up to
                        date
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.3.07</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added
                        <code>@break</code>
                        attribute to page breaks (<code>pb</code>) so
                        words can be broken over page breaks as well now!
                    </li>
                    <li>Tweaked the look n' feel of page breaks - less white space below them
                        now
                    </li>
                    <li>Changed the
                        <code>background-color</code>
                        for abbreviations
                        (<code>abbr</code>) so they're easier to differentiate from expansions
                        (<code>expan</code>)
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.3.06</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>New buttons for inserting:
                        <br/>
                        <code>opener</code>,<code>closer</code>,<code>postscript</code>, and
                        <code>respStmt</code>
                    </li>
                    <li>The keys for the
                        <code>respStmt</code>
                        were taken from the
                        <a
                                href="http://www.loc.gov/marc/relators/relacode.html">MARC Code List for
                            Relators
                        </a>
                        <br/>
                        It's an international standard used by librarians - only a small
                        subset are available on the list.
                    </li>
                    <li>When adding a new
                        <code>respStmt</code>
                        a dialog box appears where you can
                        select them from the list.
                        <br/>
                        (Unfortunately) it has to be done twice to
                        fill in the key and the label, but hey you won't be adding it
                        <i>that</i>
                        often, right?
                    </li>
                    <li>Needed more screen space, so there is now an
                        <i>Insert</i>
                        menu on the
                        <i>Sections</i>
                        toolbar
                        <br/>
                        From there, you can insert larger
                        sections, like the newly added ones as well as
                        <code>div</code>
                        's
                    </li>
                    <li>Fixed a bug: dropdown lists weren't refreshing after inserting new facsimile
                        elements:
                        <code>graphic</code>
                        and
                        <code>media</code>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="header">Version 0.3.05</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Dropdown boxes now appear when the element has focus instead of when
                        hovering over it with the mouse<br/>(Except for elements that don't have
                        text, like<code>gap</code>,<code>handShift</code>, and<code>ptr</code>)
                    </li>
                    <li>Increased speed for large documents ('Twas a wee bit sluggish)</li>
                    <li>Minor bug fixes with paths and dropdown list contents</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </xt:description>
        <xt:license><![CDATA[END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT
            
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Mike Olson

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.]]></xt:license>
    </xt:extension>
</xt:extensions>
